Alex Wendland

PHONE: +44 7854033626 GitHub: https://github.com/AlexWendland E-MAIL: alex@wendland.org.uk

WEBSITE: https://alex-wendland.notion.site/Alex-Wendland-1c54946631524bc88doa8f2c9fa16f08

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an ethical data specialist with a passion for automation, mathematics and most importantly solving problems. I apply the scientific method (ideate-test-learn-repeat) in all layers of my life. I have lead projects, teams and organisations with a focus on sustainable learning, efficiency and communication.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2021-CURRENT

Data Scientist - CRYPTOCOMPARE, LONDON

- · Researched and developed a data pipeline to collect, process and store blockchain data.
- Developed a CI/CD pipeline for our data monitoring microservices using docker, github actions, Azure cloud storage and kubernetes.
- Sought out and built relationships with established data analytics and visualisation providers to build a long-term mutually-beneficial partnership.
- Worked with clients to research, formalise, and implement metrics on TB's of data.
- Created and led the product development team to deliver multiple new products to market.
- Formed a cross-team data organisation to improve collaboration, coding standards, and knowledge of our tech stack.
- Set up and ran monthly educational seminars on blockchain data with attendance of over 20 people.

2020-2021

Civil Service, Science and Engineering Fast Stream - CABINET OFFICE, LONDON

- Project-managed high-profile technical reports with multiple stakeholders within the Advisory Council for the Misuse of Drugs: ACMD advice on consumer cannabidiol (CBD) products and Consideration of barriers to research: part 1.
- Managed internal stakeholders by developing road maps, regular updates, and resolving different requirements, and external stakeholders by organising call for evidence sessions, evidence gathering sessions, and public correspondence.
- Organised the analysis of the departmental staff survey to derive key targets and objects, increasing inclusivity and diversity.

2015-2020

Reseacher – University of Warwick

- Won multiple awards whilst building a strong academic portfolio in leading journals such as Advances in Mathematics, Annals of Applied Probability and the Journal of Graph Theory.
- Worked with Centre for Science and Policy, Heathrow airport and Defence Science and Technology Laboratory.
- Was an award winning teacher at all levels and formats: lecturing masters level courses to helping underprivileged A-Level students one-on-one.
- Earned funding in 2013 from JISC to develop a virtual learning platform in django (python).
- Chaired the main student forum for change within the department for 3 years and was an active member of our diversity committee.

EDUCATION

2015 - 2020 PhD in Mathematics, University of Warwick, Coventry

"Generalisations of Groups and Cayley Graphs" under the supervision of Agelos Georgakopoulos

2011 – 2015 Masters in MATHEMATICS, University of Warwick, Coventry

1st Class Hons (91% average)

2004 - 2011 Secondary school, Beechen Cliff School, Bath

A Levels: Further Maths (A^*) , Maths (A^*) , Physics (A)

KEY SKILLS

Developer-level languages: Python and LATEX

Working-level languages: Git, C, SQL, Bash and JavaScript

Tools: Github actions, Google suit, Docker, Kubernetes, Obsidian, notion and Web3.

Transferable: Data analysis, visualisation, and interpretation, maths, statistics,

leadership, communication, problem solving, collaboration, agile organisation,

research, relationship building, and teaching.